// Data Structure
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following usees FIFO method",
    answer: "Queue",
    options: [
      "Queue",
      "Stack",
      "Hash Table",
      "Binary Search Tree"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is the depth of the root node of the ternary tree?",
    answer: "0",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "0",
      "3"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The number of items used by the dynamic array contents is its __________",
    answer: "Logical size",
    options: [
      "Physical size",
      "Logical size",
      "Random size",
      "Capacity"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Array is divided into two parts in ____________",
    answer: "Bounded-size dynamic array",
    options: [
      "Hashed Array Tree",
      "Geometric Array",
      "Sparse Array",
      "Bounded-size dynamic array"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What is the term for inserting into a full queue known as?",
    answer: "overflow",
    options: [
      "overflow",
      "underflow",
      "null pointer exception",
      "program won’t be compiled"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What are the applications of dequeue?",
    answer: "To avoid collision in hash tables",
    options: [
      "A-Steal job scheduling algorithm",
      "Can be used as both stack and queue",
      "To avoid collision in hash tables",
      "To find the maximum of all sub arrays of size k"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The optimal data structure used to solve Tower of Hanoi is _________",
    answer: "Stack",
    options: [
      "Stack",
      "Tree",
      "Heap",
      "Priority queue"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Suffix array can be created by performing __________ traversal of a suffix tree.",
    answer: "depth-first",
    options: [
      "breadth-first",
      "level order",
      "depth-first",
      "either breadth-first or level order"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The balance factor of a node in a binary tree is defined as _____",
    answer: "height of left subtree minus height of right subtree",
    options: [
      "addition of heights of left and right subtrees",
      "height of right subtree minus one",
      "height of right subtree minus height of left subtree",
      "height of left subtree minus height of right subtree"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the worst time complexity of selection sorting?",
    answer: "O(n²) ",
    options: [
      "O(logn)",
      "O(n)",
      "O(n²) ",
      "O(nlogn)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which of the following is a Divide and Conquer algorithm?",
    answer: "Merge Sort",
    options: [
      "Selection Sort",
      "Merge Sort",
      "Heao Sort",
      "Bubble Sort"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "What is the space complexity of searching in a heap?",
    answer: "O(n)",
    options: [
      "O(logn)",
      "O(n)",
      "O(1)",
      "O(nlogn)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question:" Which of the following data structures allow insertion and deletion from both ends?",
    answer: "Deque",
    options: [
      "Array",
      "Queue",
      "Linked List",
      "Deque"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "When a pop() operation is called on an empty queue, what is the condition called",
    answer: "Underflow",
    options: [
      "Syntax Error",
      "Overflow",
      "Underflow",
      "Garbage Value"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of the following is a linear data structure?",
    answer: "Array",
    options: [
      "AVL Trees",
      "Array",
      "Binary Tree",
      "Graphs"
    ]
  },
];